Guide to the Bernard Wolfe Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Bernard Wolfe papers
1920-1998
YCAL MSS 831
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
6.46
(14 boxes)
The collection includes correspondence, writings and research material, photographs, printed material, and personal papers relating to American author Bernard Wolfe. There is correspondence, including incoming and outgoing letters, with family, friends, writers, publishers, editors, and labor organizations. Individual corrrespondents include: Pearl Buck, Marcel Duhamel, Dwight MacDonald, Henry Miller, A. J. Muste, John Crowe Ranson, Harry Ross, and Wolfe's brother Albert; there is a third-party letter from Frida Kahlo to Leon Trotsky. Writings include corrected drafts of Wolfe's best-known novels, the science-fiction work Limbo (1952) and The Great Prince Died (1959), which was based on Trotsky's assassination. Other works include an "Outline for a Study of the Role of the Negro in American Popular Culture," essays on Connecticut labor in the late 19th and early 20th centuries, and short fiction, some of which was published in Playboy in the 1960s. There are photographs, circa 1937, of Wolfe, Trotsky, Trotsky's wife Natalia Sedova, Diego Rivera, Frida Kahlo, Max Shachtman, and others. Printed materials include research material relating to Thomas Mann, clippings, and ephemera.
Wolfe, Bernard, 1915-1985
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Bernard Wolfe, 1959 and Albert Wolfe, 1990-2003.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Boxes 6 and 8 (videocassettes): Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Associated Materials
Sound recordings received as part of the April 1992 Acquisition were transferred to Historical Sound Recordings, Yale University Library.
Bernard Wolfe (1915-1985)
Bernard Wolfe, editor and author, was born in New Haven, Connecticut, on 28 August 1915 to Robert and Ida Gordon Wolfe. Wolfe was educated at Yale University (1935), where he was also a graduate student in 1935 and 1936, before he moved to Mexico to work as a secretary and translator for Leon Trotsky in 1937. Wolfe began his writing career as a freelance writer of novels and short stories and later worked as a screenwriter for Universal International Pictures, Tony Curtis Productions, and other film producers. During his writing career, Wolfe wrote in several genres, including biography, screenplays, pornography, and science fiction. For a time, he worked as a editor at Mechanix Illustrated magazine. His best-known novel, The Great Prince Died, which is based on Trostsky's assassination, was published in 1959. Wolfe's other notable work was a science-fiction novel, Limbo, published by Random House in 1952.
Biographical information taken from Guide to Literary Masters & Their Works, January 2007.
Scope and Contents
The collection includes correspondence, writings and research material, photographs, printed material, and personal papers relating to American author Bernard Wolfe. There is correspondence, including incoming and outgoing letters, with family, friends, writers, publishers, editors, and labor organizations. Individual corrrespondents include: Pearl Buck, Marcel Duhamel, Dwight MacDonald, Henry Miller, A. J. Muste, John Crowe Ranson, Harry Ross, and Wolfe's brother Albert; there is a third-party letter from Frida Kahlo to Leon Trotsky. Writings include corrected drafts of Wolfe's best-known novels, the science-fiction work, Limbo (1952), and The Great Prince Died (1959), which was based on Trotsky's assassination. Other works include an "Outline for a Study of the Role of the Negro in American Popular Culture," essays on Connecticut labor in the late 19th and early 20th centuries, and short fiction, some of which was published in Playboy in the 1960s. There are photographs, circa 1937, of Wolfe, Trotsky, Trotsky's wife Natalia Sedova, Diego Rivera, Frida Kahlo, Max Shachtman, and others. Printed materials include research material relating to Thomas Mann, clippings, and ephemera.
Arrangement
Organized into thirteen groupings: I. May 1959 Acquisition. II. April 1990 Acquisition. III. May 1991 Acquisition. IV. April 1992 Acquisition. V. September 1992 Acquisition. VI. February 1993 Acquisition. VII. December 1993 Acquisition. VIII. September 1994 Acquisition. IX. December 1997 Acquisition. X. March 1998 Acquisition. XI. September 1998 Acquisition. XII. January 1999 Acquisition. XIII. January 2003 Acquisition.
American literature -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Audiovisual materials; Photographic prints; Video recordings; Authors -- United States -- 20th Century; Buck, Pearl S. (Pearl Sydenstricker), 1892-1973; Duhamel, Marcel; Kahlo, Frida, 1907-1954; Mann, Thomas, 1875-1955; Miller, Henry, 1891-1980; Muste, A. J. (Abraham John), 1885-1967; Ransom, John Crowe, 1888-1974; Rivera, Diego, 1886-1957; Shachtman, Max, 1903-1972; Trot︠s︡kai︠a︡, Natalii︠a︡ Ivanovna, 1882-1962; Trotsky, Leon, 1879-1940; Wolfe, Bernard, 1915-1985
- May 1959 Acquisition, circa 1950s; 0.42; (1 box)
  Scope and Contents
  The May 1959 Acquisition contains a typescript draft, corrected, of Wolfe's novel about the murder of Leon Trostsky, The Great Prince Died (1959).
  Former call number: Uncat Za Wolfe.
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Gift of Bernard Wolfe, 1959
  - The Great Prince Died, draft, typescript, corrected, circa 1950s; 4 (Box 1)
- April 1990 Acquisition, 1950, undated; 0.63; (2 boxes)
  The April 1990 Acquisition contains two drafts of Wolfe's novel Limbo, one "First Draft," typescript and autograph manuscript, heavily corrected and annotated, accompanied by a typed letter signed from Wolfe to Don Congdon dating from 1951, and a later, undated typescript carbon draft.
  Former call number: Uncat Za Ms 133.
  Gift of Albert Wolfe, 1990.
  - Limbo, draft, typescript and autograph manuscript, corrected, 1950 (Box 2)
  - Limbo, draft, typescript carbon, undated (Box 3)
- May 1991 Acquisition, 1930s-1991; 0.29; (2 boxes)
  The May 1991 Acquisition contains a draft of the "Outline for a Study of the Role of the Negro in American Popular Culture," a photograph album, and a printed guide to the Max Shachtman Collection at the Tamiment Institute/Ben Josephson Library. The photograph album contains black-and-white photographs, circa 1930s, of Wolfe, Leon Trotsky, Natalia Sedova, Diego Rivera, Frida Kahlo, and others.
  Former call number: Uncat Za Ms 187.
  Gift of Albert Wolfe, 1991.
  - "Outline for a Study of the Role of the Negro in American Popular Culture," draft, typescript and typescript carbon, 1948-1950, undated; 2 (Box 3)
  - New York University Bulletin of the Tamiment Institute/Ben Josephson Library, 1983 April (Box 3)
  - Photograph album, 1930s-1991 (Box 4 (Oversize))
- April 1992 Acquisition, 1922-1985; 1; (1 box)
  Related Archival Materials note
  Sound recordings transferred to Historical Sound Recordings, Yale University Library.
  The April 1992 Acquisition consists of correspondence, writings, and other papers dating largely from the mid to late 1930s. There is correspondence between Bernard Wolfe and his brother Albert, Max Fleischman, Harry Ross, and others, including a third-party letter from Frida Kahlo to Leon Trotsky, and writings by Wolfe, Trotsky, and others. Writings by Trotsky appear to consist chiefly of copies and translations of short works made by Wolfe in his capacity as secretary and translator to Trotsky in 1937, while Trotsky lived in exile in Mexico.
  Former call number: Uncat Za Ms 229.
  Gift of Albert Wolfe, 1992.
  - Correspondence
    - Ageloff, Ruth, 1936 February 14 (Box 5)
    - Burbank, David T., 1937 (Box 5)
    - "C" general, 1937-1938 (Box 5)
    - Dagen, Irwin, 1937 May 14 (Box 5)
    - Epstein, Frank to Leon Trotsky, 1937 May 23 (Box 5)
    - Fischer, Louis, 1934 November 10 (Box 5)
    - Fleischman, Max, 1937; 2 (Box 5)
    - The Guardian, 1937 (Box 5)
    - Harde, Albert, 1937, undated; 2 (Box 5)
    - Harvard Monthly to Leon Trotsky, 1937 (Box 5)
    - Heijenoort, Jean van, 1937 September 1 (Box 5)
    - Hudson, Carlos, 1937 July 10 (Box 5)
    - Isaacs, Harold, 1937 (Box 5)
    - Kahlo, Frida to Leon Trotsky, 1937 July 12 (Box 5)
    - Karsner, Rose, 1937 May 30 (Box 5)
    - [Kluger?], Pearl, 1937 (Box 5)
    - LaFollette, Suzanne to Leon Trotsky, 1937 September 15 (Box 5)
    - Levensohn, Mike, 1935, 1937 (Box 5)
    - "M" general, 1935, 1937 (Box 5)
    - Pioneer Publishers, 1937 (Box 5)
    - Robinson, Viola, 1937 March 1 (Box 5)
    - Ross, Harry, 1937, undated (Box 5)
    - [Shambon?], Art, 1937 May 5 (Box 5)
    - Spanier, Pauline, 1937 (Box 5)
    - Speigel, Rae, 1937 September 28 (Box 5)
    - Trotsky, Leon to M. Barrué, 1937 March 10 (Box 5)
    - Wallace, B., 1937 October 25 (Box 5)
    - W[immick?], Willy, 1937 April 28 (Box 5)
    - Wolfe, Bernard to others, 1937, undated (Box 5)
    - Wolfe, Robert and Ida, 1937 (Box 5)
    - Workers Party of U. S., 1935 February 19 (Box 5)
    - Yale Daily News, 1937 (Box 5)
    - ----, [Jan?], 1937 (Box 5)
    - Unidentified, 1937, undated (Box 5)
  - Writings
    - Writings of Bernard Wolfe
      - "The 'Darks' Against the 'Lights'," article, printed version, photocopy, 1960 April (Box 5)
      - Logan's Gone, review, "Who's Been Keeping This Wolfe From Our Door," by Harlan Ellison, printed version (photocopy), 1974 November 10 (Box 5)
      - "Lou Meyer: A Roundabout Road Trip," typescript (photostat), corrected and annotated, undated; 2 (Box 5)
      - "Memoirs of a Not Altogether Shy Pornographer," book review, printed version, photocopy, 1972 October 22 (Box 5)
      - "Mr. Beals Inexplicable Change of Mind," typescript carbon, 1937 May 28 (Box 5)
      - "The 'New Republic's' Embarrassing Investigation," typescript carbon, corrected, 1937 May 26 (Box 5)
      - Notes, autograph manuscript, undated (Box 5)
      - Really the Blues, advance proofs, undated (Box 5)
      - "A Woman Is Beaten," typescript (photocopy), undated (Box 5)
      - Unidentified work, typescript and typescript carbon, corrected, 1943, undated; 8 (Box 5)
    - Writings of Leon Trotsky
      - [André Malraux], typescript, corrected, and typescript carbon, 1937, undated (Box 5)
      - "Answer To the Questions of Wendelin Thomas," typescript carbon, 1937 July 6 (Box 5)
      - "The Arrest of Sergei Sedov, My Younger Son," typescript carbon, corrected, 1937 January 27 (Box 5)
      - "Comment et pourquoi des citoyens sovietiques s'accusent-ils de crimes qu'ils n'ont pas commis?" typescript, corrected, 1937 January 29 (Box 5)
      - "The Construction of the Trial," typescript, corrected, 1937 January 30 (Box 5)
      - "La construction du procés," typescript, corrected, 1937 January 30 (Box 5)
      - "The Conveyor of Frameups at Work," typescript, corrected, undated (Box 5)
      - "The Danzig Trial of the Trotskyists," typescript carbon, corrected, 1937 April 29 (Box 5)
      - "Dear Listeners, Comrades, and Friends," typescript carbon (2 copies), undated (Box 5)
      - "The Decapitation of the Red Army," typescript, corrected, and typescript carbon (2 copies), 1937 June 12 (Box 5)
      - "Declaration Regarding the Case of Senin and Well," typescript carbon (2 copies), 1937 February 27 (Box 5)
      - "Les dernieres paroles des accuses," typescript, corrected, 1937 January 30 (Box 5)
      - "Il faut une revue Marxiste Militante, Revolutionaire, Critique," typescript carbon, 1937 May 29 (Box 5)
      - "Fenner Brockway, Pritt No. 2," typescript, corrected, 1937 March 6 (Box 5)
      - "Finale?" typescript, corrected, 1937 February 1 (Box 5)
      - "The Hotel Bristol," typescript, corrected, and typescript carbon, corrected, 1937 March 18 (Box 5)
      - "How and Why Did Soviet Citizens Accuse Themselves of Crimes Which They Did Not Commit?" typescript, corrected, and typescript carbon, 1937 January (Box 5)
      - "An Incomprehensible Polemical Sally from M. Troyanovsky," typescript, corrected, in French and English versions, 1937, undated (Box 5)
      - "Japan and China," typescript, corrected, 1937 July 30 (Box 5)
      - "My Concrete Proposition to the Moscow Court," typescript, corrected, and typescript carbon (3 copies), 1937 January 27 (Box 5)
      - "My Task Before the Commission," typescript carbon, undated (Box 5)
      - "One More Fake Testimony," autograph manuscript and typescript, corrected, 1937 February 24 (Box 5)
      - "Ou est Sosnovski?" typescript carbon, 1937 February 25 (Box 5)
      - "Pourquoi la Guepeou a-t-elle choisi le mois de decembre?" typescript, corrected [by Leon Trotsky?], undated (Box 5)
      - "The Preparation by Trotskyites of War Against the Soviet Union," typescript, corrected, 1937 January 28 (Box 5)
      - "A 'Purely Juridical' Opinion," typescript, corrected, 1937 March 22 (Box 5)
      - "Series of Amalgams," typescript carbon, 1927-1937 (Box 5)
      - "Some Concrete Questions to Mr. Malraux," typescript, corrected, and typescript carbon, 1937 March 13 (Box 5)
      - ["The Swedish Party of Kilboom..."], typescript, corrected, in French and English versions, 1937 February 19 (Box 5)
      - "The Testimonies of Vladimir Room Unmasked:," typescript, corrected, and typescript carbon, 1937 February 15 (Box 5)
      - "Text of Mr. Trotsky's Address to Newsreels," typescript, corrected, in French and English versions, 1937 January 30 (Box 5)
      - "To the Commission of Inquiry: Mr. Beals as a Witness," typescript carbon, 1937 May 18 (Box 5)
      - "To the Sub-Commission of Inquiry: Explanation Regarding My Turkish Passport, Granted July 12, 1933," typescript carbon, 1937 May 27 (Box 5)
      - Untitled, 1937, undated; 2 (Box 5)
    - Writings of Others
      - Gold, Michael. "America Needs a Critic," review of an unidentified work by Leon Trotsky, typescript carbon, 1926 October (Box 5)
      - Grobel, Larry. "Bernard Wolfe: The Writer as Hero," printed version (photocopy), 1975 September 12 (Box 5)
      - Heijenoort, Jean van. "Some Revealing Documents," typescript, 1937 February 13 (Box 5)
      - Novo, Salvador. "Moscow-Coyoacan," typescript carbon, 1937 May 8 (Box 5)
      - Sedova-Trotskaia, Natalia. "A la conscience du monde entier!" typescript, corrected, 1937 February (Box 5)
      - Silone, Ignazio. "A Letter from Silone," translation, typescript, 1936 September 24 (Box 5)
  - Other Papers
    - Announcement of talk: "What is Happening in Russia?" by Bernard Wolfe and Robert Graves, photocopy, 1937 November 23 (Box 5)
    - Answers to Questions, undated (Box 5)
    - "Concerning Shachtman's Meeting with Trotsky on July 24th, 1933," typescript carbon, corrected, 1937 February 26 (Box 5)
    - Information Bulletin of the P. O. U. M, 1936 September 29 (Box 5)
    - "Leon Trotsky's Final Speech to the Preliminary Commission of Inquiry," typescript mimeograph, 1937 April 17 (Box 5)
    - List, typescript, annotated, undated (Box 5)
    - Map of North Arabia, War Office, 1922 March (Box 5)
    - Clippings, 1937, undated; 3 (Box 5)
    - Open letter to Lion Feuchtwanger, typescript carbon (2 copies), 1937 February 20 (Box 5)
    - Press statements, 1937 (Box 5)
    - Quotations and excerpts from newspapers and magazines relating to Leon Trotsky and the U.S.S.R., typescript and typescript carbon, 1931-1937 (Box 5)
    - [Sources], typescript carbon, undated (Box 5)
    - Bernard Wolfe obituaries, 1985 (Box 5)
    - Empty folders, undated (Box 5)
    - Empty envelopes, undated (Box 5)
- September 1992 Acquisition, 1930s-1990; 0.42; (1 box)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Box 6 (videocassettes): Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  The September 1992 Acquisition includes correspondence, financial records, photographs, printed material, and videocassettes relating to Wolfe and/or Trotsky.
  Former call number: Uncat Za Ms 263.
  - Bill submitted to Standard Oil Company, 1943 January 12 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence, 1941-1948, undated (Box 6)
    Includes nine typed letters, signed from Wolfe to his mother and one typed letter, signed to Wolfe from Hopewell Rogers
  - "Leon Trotsky en Mexico City (Coyoqcah): Filmado por Alex Buchman, entre Noviembre 1939 y Abril 1940", undated; 1; 00:29:32; Audio cannot be heard. (Box 6, Item barcode 39002091396094)
  - Photographs, 1930s, undated (Box 6)
  - Printed material, 1960 April; 3 (Box 6)
  - Scholarship announcement, 1934 July 16 (Box 6)
  - "'Trotsky' - A Two-Part, Two-Hour Telefilm by Ima of Paris", undated; 1; 02:01:04; Video levels vary throughtout the program. (Box 6, Item barcode 39002091396102)
  - "'Trotsky's Home Movies", A British Channel 4 Production, 1990 August 20; 1; 00:40:43; Video levels vary througout the program. (Box 6, Item barcode 39002091396110)
    Broadcast on the 50th anniversary of LDT's assassination.
- February 1993 Acquisition, 1937
  The February 1993 Acquisition consists of four photographs: two photographs of Leon Trotsky, inscribed by Trotsky to Wolfe; one photograph of Trotsky and Diego Rivera, also inscribed by Trotsky to Wolfe; and one photograph including Trotsky, Natalia Sedova, Frida Kahlo, and Max Shachtman.
  Former call number: Uncat Za File 293.
  Gift of Albert Wolfe, 1993.
  - Photographs, 1937 (Box 7)
- December 1993 Acquisition, 1937; 0.21; (1 box)
  The December 1993 Acquisition consists of nine color photographs of Leon Trotsky, three with Natalia Sedova, by A. H. Buchman, as well as a manuscript by Richard Wright, inscribed by Bernard Wolfe.
  Former call number: Uncat Za Ms 313.
  - Photographs, undated (Box 7)
  - "A Hitherto Unpublished Manuscript by Richard Wright Being a Continuation of Black Boy..." printed version, undated (Box 7)
- September 1994 Acquisition, 1934-1979; 0.42; (1 box)
  The September 1994 Acquisition contains correspondence and printed material. There are letters between Bernard Wolfe and his brother Albert, Warren C. Montross, A. J. Muste, and others. Printed materials include a version of the a story "Self Portrait".
  Former call number: Uncat Za Ms 411.
  Gift of Albert Wolfe, 1994.
  - Correspondence, 1934-1938, undated; 6 (Box 8)
  - Empty envelopes, undated (Box 8)
  - Printed ephemera, 1934-1979, ndated (Box 8)
  - "Self Portrait," story, printed version, Galaxy: Science Fiction, 1951 November (Box 8)
- December 1997 Acquisition, undated
  Box 8 (videocassette): Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  The December 1997 Acquisition consists of a single videocassette containing a Spanish documentary, entitled "Asaltar Los Cielos (Assault the Heavens)," on Ramon Mercader, the man who assassinated Leon Trotsky in Mexico in 1940.
  Former call number: Uncat Za Ms 543.
  Gift of Albert Wolfe, 1997.
  - "Asaltar Los Cielos ("Assault the Heavens"), undated; 1; 01:35:22; There is a high amount of hiss on the tape. (Box 8, Item barcode 39002091396086)
    This is a Spanish documentary on Ramon Mercader, the assassin of Trotsky. Substitles are in English. It runs approximately 1 1/2 hours.
- March 1998 Acquisition, 1937-1949; 0.42; (1 box)
  The March 1998 Acquisition consists chiefly of unsorted correspondence, including incoming and outgoing letters with family, friends, writers, publishers, editors, and labor organizations. Corrrespondents include: Pearl [Buck?], Marcel Duhamel, Dwight MacDonald, Henry Miller, John Crowe Ranson, and others. Also includes biographical material.
  Former call number: Uncat Za Ms 555.
  Gift of Albert Wolfe, 1998.
  - Correspondence, circa 1937-1949, undated; 10 (Box 9)
  - Biographical information, undated (Box 9)
- September 1998 Acquisition, 1960-1998; 0.21; (1 box)
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically by title.
  The September 1998 Acquisition contains photocopies and printed versions of short writings by Wolfe and others, including short stories, articles, and interviews. Stories includes: "The Never Ending Penny," "Come On Out, Daddy," and other works. The dates listed below are publication dates.
  Former call number: Uncat Za Ms 569.
  - "Agoraphobia Is in the Public Domain," story, printed version (photocopy), Playboy, 1961 November (Box 10)
  - "Anthony from Afar," story, printed version (photocopy), Playboy, 1962 February (Box 10)
  - "Bernard Wolfe and the Novel of the Fifties" by Gregory Feeley, article, printed version, Bookman's Weekly, 1998 August 3 (Box 10)
  - "Come on Out, Daddy," story, printed version (photocopy), Playboy, 1961 February (Box 10)
  - "The Dot and Dash Bird," story, printed version (photocopy), Playboy, 1964 December (Box 10)
  - "The Going Price for Adoration," printed version (photocopy), Playboy, 1963 October (Box 10)
  - "Henry Miller," interview, reprint, 1964 (Box 10)
  - "The Hot Sauces of Magda," story, printed version (photocopy), Playboy, 1968 February (Box 10)
  - "How Simon Got His Bureau," story, printed version (photocopy), Playboy, 1966 February (Box 10)
  - List of publications by Wolfe, undated (Box 10)
  - "Marcianna and the Natural Carpaine in Papaya," story, printed version (photocopy), Playboy, 1961 June (Box 10)
  - "The Never Ending Penny," story, printed version (photocopy), 1960 September (Box 10)
  - "The Roach Powder in the Maple Walnut," story, printed version (photocopy), Playboy, 1966 May (Box 10)
  - "Sue Me Rich," story, printed version (photocopy), Playboy, 1964 October (Box 10)
  - "Swimming in Red Ink," story, printed version (photocopy), Playboy, 1964 July (Box 10)
  - "What's in a Name?" by Leonard Lyons, article, printed version (photocopy), Playboy, 1960 September (Box 10)
  - "Whispers in Bedlam" by Irwin Shaw, story, printed version (photocopy), Playboy, undated (Box 10)
- January 1999 Acquisition, 1920s-1961; 2.25; (3 boxes)
  The January 1999 Acquisition contains correspondence, research material relating to Thomas Mann, drafts of writings, legal records, and printed material.
  Former call number: Uncat Za Ms 606.
  Gift of Albert Wolfe, 1999.
  - "Publishers", circa 1954-1959 (Box 11)
  - "The Congo on Main Street", undated; 6 (Box 11)
  - "From the Solid to the Frantic: The Somewhereness of Bop", undated (Box 11)
  - Boards, undated; 2 (Box 11)
  - "Outline for a Study of the Role of the Negro in American Popular Culture", undated; 3 (Box 11)
  - "Uncle Remus and the Malevolent Rabbit: A Note on Folkey Falsefaces", undated (Box 11)
  - "Murray Teigh Bloom, Plaintiff, against national Broadcasting Company, Philco Corporation, and Bernard Wolfe, Defendants", 1955 December 19 (Box 11)
  - "Memorandum of Agreement", 1945 April 23 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence, 1945-1948, undated; 7 (Box 11)
  - Miscellaneous manuscript material, undated; 10 (Box 11)
  - Printed ephemera, 1942-1945, undated; 3 (Box 11)
  - "Reviews- Really the Blues ", circa 1946 (Box 11)
  - Clipping, [1948?] January 12 (Box 11)
  - Receipts, 1947 June 9 (Box 11)
  - Empy folder, undated (Box 11)
  - "The Business", undated (Box 11)
  - "Publishers--Corres., Contracts", 1945-1948, undated (Box 11)
  - "Surrealism", 1940s (Box 11)
  - "Connecticut Labor, 1877-1914", 1939 July 18 (Box 11)
  - "Connecticut in the Early Nineteenth Century: A State in Transition", undated (Box 11)
  - Correspondence, 1947-1948, undated; 12 (Box 12)
  - "Connecticut Labor from 1850 To 1877", undated (Box 12)
  - Material relating to Thomas Mann and German culture, 1920s-1940s; 27 (Box 12)
  - Agreement with Random House, 1945 May 15 (Box 12)
  - Clippings, 1941-1960, undated; 14 (Box 12)
  - Printed ephemera, 1948-1958, undated; 13 (Box 12)
  - "The Intentional Town", 1946, undated; 13 (Box 12)
  - "The Late Risers: A Musical Play", undated (Box 12)
  - "Here Live Lions", undated (Box 12)
  - Unidentified manuscript, undated (Box 12)
  - Miscellaneous manuscript material, undated; 11 (Box 12)